Guide to the Robert Sutherland Lord Papers, 1890-2013 UA.90.F101
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Research Files, 1889-2013; IV.
  - Charles Tournemire, 1889-2012; 5.
    - Publisher's Contract for Book Chapter, April 2012 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Archbold, Lawrence, program notes for an organ recital of works by Cesar Franck, Carleton College, 1988-1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Cogen, Pierre (correspondence with Lord; photographs of Cogen), 1889-1993 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Daniel-Lesur (correspondence with Lord), 1976-1988 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Interview of Norbert Dufoureq, Madame Soudere by Robert Sutherland Lord, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Eschbach, Jesse E., "Cons Ms [8707: A New Source for César Franck's Registrational Practices and its Implications for the Published Registrations of his Organ Works," typescript, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Fauquet, Joel-Marie, Program note for an organ recital of Tournemire's Seven Chorals-Poemes by Lord in Saint-Clotilde, typescript (in French and English), undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
      Offprint of Fauquet's article "Alexis de Castillon, sa vie, son oeuvre," Bulletin de la Société archéologique d'Eure-et-Loir (1978): inscribed to Lord on the cover
    - Correspondence: Fauqet, Joel-Marie (ALS and a postcard), 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Fleury, André, program to organ recital, Cathedrale Saint-Louis de Versailles, and 3 photographs of Fleury taken at the Lord residence, 1982, May 1989 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Grimes, Robert R., "Evolution and Context of the Gregorian Revival, final project, Historical Musicology (typescript), May 1989 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Péladan, Joséphin (Sâr), 1859-1918, articles on the playright and research notes by Lord, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Solesmes, discography and article on Gregorian chant use at Solesmes), 1985 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Sisson, Ruth, "The Thematic Process in Tournemire's Organ Music of the 1930's," paper given at the St. Paul Symposium, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - "César Franck (1822-1890)," compilation by Russell Saunders, Eastman School of Music, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - McIlwrath, Isa Roberta, "Charles Tournemire and His Organ Works" (MA Thesis, Columbia University), photocopy of typescript, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Mitchell, Ernest, correspondence for Lord's research. Includes photograph of Mitchell, 1977-1980 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Peeters, Flor; publications about and by Peeters, 1973-1978 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Walker, Tom; program of the artist's "The Mystic Image," an exhibition of paintings inspired by Tournemire's L'Orgue mystique, Lutheran Brotherhood Gallery, Minneapolis, MN, October 1-30, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Research Materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 32-33)
    - Oussant, Ile du Ponant, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Articles on Tournemire by Flor Peeters and Norbert Dufourcq in Musica Sacra and L'Orgue, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Articles on Tournemire by Flor Peeters, 1940-1964 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Bref de Paris (photocopy), 1859 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Tournemire's Copy of Peladan's Babylone (photocopy), 1893 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Tournemire's Copy of Peladan's De Parsifal á Don Quichotte (photocopy), 1906 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Tournemire's VIII Symphonie: La Symphonie du Temple de la Mort, op. 51 (photocopy of manuscript), 1921 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Drafts of Works in Progress by Robert Sutherland Lord, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Writings: "Chapter Eight, Charles Tournemire: Mystical Dissonance", undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - "Charles Tournemire and the Seven Last Words of Christ," Lord's original typescript of the article and a copy of the published work, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Research notes on the secret melody in Tournemire's L'Orgue mystique (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Research notes on the use of Gregorian chants in L'Orgue mystique (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Review of the published edition of Tournemire's "Fantaisie Symphonique Op. 64 for Organ", edited by Thomas Daniel Schlee, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Naji Hakim, "A Study in Interpretation: Fresque Symphonique Sacree (Op. 76)," unpublished typescript (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - "Liturgy & Gregorian Chant in L'Orgue mystique of Charles Tournemire, " by Robert Sutherland Lord, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 48)
      Expanded version of paper given at the 1979 AMS meeting in New York.
    - "La Liturgie et le Chant Grégorian dans L'Orgue mystique de Charles Tournemire." French translation of above; photocopy of typescript, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Research Notes on Les Brouillons de L'Orgue Mystique (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - "Liturgy & Gregorian Chant in L'Orgue Mystiue of Charles Tournemire," correction to study in Folder 41 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Tournemire, "La classe d'orgue du Conservatoire de Paris," (L'Orgue et les Organistes (Le monde musical, April 1930), photocopy (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Chants used by Ch. Tournemire in "Holy Saturday Office (#16): L'Orgue Mystique", mimeographed handout, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Charles Tournemire L'Orgue Mystique "Les Brouillons," catalog of Paris, Bibliotheque nationale Ms. 19929 prepared by Lord, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - "Organ Works of Charles Tournemire," list prepared by Lord, arranged by opus number, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Research materials on chant and French liturgy (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "The Sketchbook for Charles Tournemire's L'Orgue Mystique," typescript, with Lord's corrections (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "New Insights into the Creative Process in Charles Tournemire's L'Orgue Mystique" by Robert Sutherland Lord, typescript, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Research notes on the "Non-Organ Works", ca. 1978 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "The Sainte Clotilde Tradition",and "Liturgy and the Organ at the Basilica of Sainte-Clotilde, Paris from 1858 to 1940," includes handwritten rsearch notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Notes on the Program "The Sainte Clotilde Tradition", typescript, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "The Sainte Clotilde Tradition", Outline of a talk given at Duquesne University; typescript, February 20, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "César Franck and the Sainte Clotilde Tradition", undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Information on Sainte Clotilde and its annual music festival of organ music, 1970-1989 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Sainte Clotilde Research File, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Sainte Clotilde Research File, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - L'orgue de Choeur de L'Eglise Sainte Clotilde, by MM. Merklin. Published description of the organ at Sainte-Clotilde, 1888 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Sainte Clotilde, Duquesne University, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Sainte Clotilde Concert Programs by Tournemire and of his works by others, 1923-1938 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Sept Chorales-Poems D'Orgue Notes, and "Charles Tournemire On the High Mission of the Church Organist (De la Haute Mission de l'organiste à l;église). Lecture submitted for the Russell Saunders Memorial Lectures, undated, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence with Norbert Dufourcq and Arthur Lawrence about the article "Tournemire et Sept Chorales-Poems d'Orgue" (1/2); with handwritten research notes, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Version in English for French translation of "Charles Tournemire and Sept Chorales-Poems d'Orgue" (2/2); and the French translation, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "Study of Organ Works by Tournemire", undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "Charles Tournemire and The Seven Words of Christ on the Cross"; English version submitted to The Diapason, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - The Suite Medievale: Jean Langlais and the "Tournemire" Tradition, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Notes on "La doulouresse Passion de Notre-Seigneur Jésus Christ", undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - L'Orgue Mystique Research Notes, ca. 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - L'Orgue Mystique Research Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
    - "New Insights into the Creative Process in Charles Tournemire's L'Orgue Mystique"; typescript and research notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Remarks given at the 50th anniversary of Tournemire's death; in French, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Untitled Essay on Tournemire's L'Orgue mystique, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - The 1933 Rebuilding of the Cavaillé-Coll Organ in the Basilica of Ste. Clotilde, Paris: Tournemire's Blueprint for the Console, typescript, with handout, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Liturgy and the Organ at the Basilica of Sainte-Clotilde in Paris during the Time of César Franck and Charles Tournemire (1859-1940), outline of article or presentation, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Writings by Lawrence Archbold, including abstract of a book project and on Tournemire's recording of Franck's A minor chorale; typescript, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Lord's English translation of Charles Tournemire, César Franck (Paris: Delagrave), in typescript and handwritten, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Photocopy of Charles Tournemire, César Franck (Paris: Delagrave, 1931) (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Organ Symphonies Research Notes; handwritten, undated (Box 8, Folder 33-34)
    - Research notes on Tournemire; various published and unpublished sources, undated (Box 8, Folder 35-36)
    - Research Notes on Tournemire, with the handwritten text of a presentation on L'Orgue mystique given in St. Paul, MN, July 15, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 37-38)
    - Research Notes on Tournemire, including biography, and the organ renovations in Ste. Clotilde, 1859-1962 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Research Notebooks on L'Orgue mystique, undated (Box 8, Folder 40-42)
    - Handout for Edward Schaefer's presentation "Tournemire's L'Orgue mystique and its Place in the Legacy of the Organ Mass," Gregorian Chant and Modern Composition for the Catholic Liturgy: Charles Tournemire's L'Orgue Mystique as Guide; Miami, February 2012 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Conference Materials for Gregorian Chant and Modern Composition for the Catholic Liturgy: Charles Tournemire's L'Orgue Mystique as Guide, and The Aesthetics and Pedagogy of Charles Tournemire: Chant and Improvisation in the Liturgy (Duquesne University), 2012 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Notes and Research Materials, ca. 1989 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Research Notebooks, undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Handwritten Research Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Tournemire Research Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Photocopies of Tournemire's letters, 1928-1935 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Photocopy of Charles Tournemire: Mystical Dissonance,: in Mystic Modernism: Catholic Visions of the Real (pp. 283-322) (Box 8, Folder 50-53)
    - Analysis of the manuscript Tournemire's Sketchbook for L'Orgue Mystique and L'Orgue glorieux, undated (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Bibliographical Index Cards for Tournemire Research, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Material relating to ICSOM, the Institute for Critical Studies of Organ Music, including correspondence, minutes, and the Tournemire Event Newsletter (vol. 1: no. 1, 3-5), 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Program with abstracts and selected papers for the symposium "Ch. Tournemire in Saint Paul", July 15-16, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Tournemire Research File (Oversize 15)
      This box contains oversized photocopies of sheet music found in Dr. Lord's original Tournemire Research file.
    - Tournemire Research File (Oversize 16)
    - L'Orgue Mystique and Sept Chorals (Oversize 17)
      Custom box containing Dr. Lord's copy of Tournemire's L'Orgue Mystique and Sept Chorales (incomplete set)
    - L'Orgue Mystique (Oversize 18)
      Custom box containing Dr. Lord's photocopies of Tournemire's L'Orgue Mystique (incomplete set)
    - Incipits of Gregorian chants by feasts of the church year. Manuscript (in Tournemire's hand?) (Box 19, Oversize 4)
    - 3 Piéces pour le grand orgue, César Franck (Box 19, Oversize 5)
      Tournemire's copy? Numerous markings in blue and red pencil.
    - L'Orgue Mystique. Cycle de Noël. No. 7. Epiphania Domini. Section 4-5 (original sheet music by Tournemire), ca. 1927 (Box 19, Oversize 6)
- Departmental and Administrative Files, 1950-2007; V.
  This series is comprised of three subseries: general departmental records; teaching files; and records concerning the Heinz Chapel Renovations. Files of interest found here are Dr. Lord's administrative files both as the University Organist and as the Music Department Chair. Other items of interest in this series are syllabi and exams from two of Dr. Lord's Music classes. The largest subseries is that concerning Heinz Chapel. This series is further organized chronologically to reflect the organ's life cycle. Records regarding Dr. Lord's initial 1963-1965 survey of the original Aeolian-Skinner Opus 922 can be found first, followed by records concerning the 1971 renovation into the Moller Opus 19642 instrument, then finally records concerning the 1995 renovation into the Reuter Opus 2176.
  - Administrative Records, 1962-2007; 1.
    - Activities Report, 1979-1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Music Department Reports, 1969-1988 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Chancellor Posvar, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Frick Organ, 1984-2004 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Heinz Chapel Dedication Concert, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - University Honors Societies, 1976-1999 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Lord Retirement Lunch, 2000-2008 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Frick Fine Arts Organ, 1962-1966 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - John Heinz Memorial Service, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Heinz Chapel Administrative Documents, 1962-1972 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Heinz Chapel Organ, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Departmental Documents, 1962-2007 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Moller Practice Organ, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Heinz Chapel Organ Renovation, 1962-1999; 2.
    - Heinz Chapel Study, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Letters of Support and Concern, 1964-1999 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Proposal with Casavant Organ Company, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Aeolian-Skinner, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Aeolian-Skinner Promotional Material, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Specifications, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - General Correspondence, 1963-1971 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Proposals for Renovation, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Campus Physical Proposal, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Moller, Inc., 1964-1969 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Moller Blueprints, undated (Box 9, Folder 30-31)
    - Moller, Inc. Promotional Material, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 32-33)
    - Renovation Proposals, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Moller Files, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Renovation Records, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Henry D. Salmen, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Reuter Proposal, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Reuter Notebook, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Class Files, 1950-1999; 3.
    - Lecture Notes (Davidson College), 1962 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Student Gift from Music 32, March 1999 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Music 32, undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Music 32 Evaluations, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Music 80, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Music 80 Evaluations, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 45-46)
    - Dissertation Oversight, January 1985 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Teaching Notes, 1960-1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Teaching Notes Music 80, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Classical Music, 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Lecture Materials Music 31, ca. 1981-1983 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Lecture Materials Music 31, undated (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
    - Lecture Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
    - Various Notes, Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - School Notes, 1950-1951 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Various Lecture Materials, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Lecture Materials on Mozart, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Lecture Materials on Bach, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Lecture Materials Music 211, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Lecture Slides, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Professional Associations, 1953-2012; VI.
  This series offers materials relating to Dr. Lord's professional activity as an organist outside of the University of Pittsburgh. These materials come from Dr. Lord's time with the American Guild of Organists, the various churches he worked for throughout his career, the International Charles Tournemire Association, and the Pittsburgh public broadcasting station, WQED.
  - American Guild of Organists, 1987-2009 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - American Guild of Organists: Pittsburgh Pipelines, 2006-2007 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Autograph Book: First Presbyterian Church of Edgewood, 1956-1959 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Davidson College Yearbook, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Associations, 1964-1999 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Christ Episcopal Church Retirement, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Christ Episcopal Church Annuals, 1987-1996 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Christ Episcopal Church, Winter 1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Organ Yearbook, 1982-1985 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra, March 1987 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - American Guild of Organists Syracuse Convention, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - American Guild of Organists Conference, 2012 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - American Guild of Organists, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - American Musicological Society, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Christ Episcopal Church, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Christ Episcopal Church Annual Reports, 1973-1976 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Christ Episcopal Church Annual Reports, 1977-1981 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Christ Episcopal Church Directories, 1973-1996 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Clough Genealogical Society Bulletins, 1961-1985 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Davidson College, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Edgewood Church, May 1959 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - First Presbyterian Church, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Friends of Charles Tournemire, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - International Charles Tournemire Association Inc, 2012 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Selwyn Avenue Presbyterian Church, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - St. Peter's Episcopal Church, 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Tournemire Conference, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - WQED: Lord on Bach Scripts & Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 23-24)
  - WQED: Lord on Buxtehude Scripts & Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Printed Material, 1889-2006; VII.
  The Printed Materials series is further organized into three subseries with one additional item not subdivided. The programs subseries contains programs from recitals, concerts, and any other performance Dr. Lord played in or attended throughout his career. The Newspaper clippings subseries contains excerpts from newspapers Dr. Lord selected from local and national new sources, as well as from certain professional newsletters and magazines. The final subseries features historic and decorative sheet music that were possible gifts to Dr. Lord.
  - Programs and Announcements, 1945-2006; 1.
    - Churches A-B, 1957-1999 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - American Guild of Organists Concerts and Conferences, 1959-1973 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - American Guild of Organists Concerts and Conferences, 1980-2006 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Churches C-E, 1945-1996 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Christ Episcopal Church, 1963-1983 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Christ Episcopal Church, 1984-2009 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Davidson College, 1959-1962 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Edgewood Congregational Church, 1954-1957 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Edgewood Congregational Church, 1957-1960 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Churches F-H, 1962-1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - First Presbyterian Church (Bridgeport, Conneticut), 1953-1959 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Venues in France, 1957-2000 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Frick Fine Arts and Carnegie Music Hall, 1963-1989 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Hebron United Presbyterian Church, 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Heinz Chapel, 1960-1969 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Heinz Chapel, 1970-1979 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Heinz Chapel, 1980-1989 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Heinz Chapel, 1990-1999 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Heinz Chapel, 2000s and undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Heinz Christmas Dinners, 1987-2001 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Churches L-P, 1957-2002 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Churches R-Z, 1954-1996 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Smithfield Church, 1967-1972 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Selwyn Avenue Presbyterian Church, 1958-1961 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - St. Paul's (Several Churches), 1962-1989 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - St. Peter's Episcopal Church, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Trinity (Several Churches), 1957-1997 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Other Churches Named After Saints, 1957-2002 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Other Universities, 1958-2007 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Other University of Pittsburgh Events, 1965-1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Concerts at an Unknown Location, 1959-1994 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Large Programs, Various, 1967-1988 (Box 14, Oversize 5)
  - Newspapers, 1889-2000s; 2.
    - News Clippings, 1950-1959 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - News Clippings, 1960-1965 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - News Clippings, 1966-1969 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - News Clippings, 1970-1979 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - News Clippings, 1980-1989 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - News Clippings, 1990-1995 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - News Clippings, 1996-1999 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - News Clippings, 2000's (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - News Clippings, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - News Clippings: The Etude, 1896 (Box 14, Oversize 3)
  - Decorative or Historic Sheet Music, 3.
    - Trio: Return, O wand'rer, from the Juvenile Harmonist, 1855 (Box 19, Oversize 7)
    - My uncle / written by a Gentleman; the music by J. Townsend, ca. 1830 (Oversize 8)
  - Commercially Printed Materials, 4.
    - Commercially Printed Materials (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Photographic Material, VIII.
  The photographic materials section maintains both personal photographs of Dr. Lord and his family as well as an assortment of professional headshots. Photographs of interest include those of Dr. Lord in association with other organist such as Jean Langlais, and photographs of Dr. Lord's visits to various churches and organs around the world.
  - Robert Lord (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Lord in Performance (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Personal Photographs (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Heinz Chapel Organ (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Heinz Organ (Box 13, Folder 19-20)
  - Heinz Organ Negatives (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Vacation in Bordeaux: St. Croix (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Vacation in Bordeaux: Cathedrale de St. Andre (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Vacation in Bordeaux: Eglise St. Pierre (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Vacation in Bordeaux: Basilique St. Seurin (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Vacation in Arachon: Tombeau de La Famille Tournemire (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Organs, April 1966 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Organs (Box 13, Folder 28-31)
  - Organs Negatives (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Church Organ (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Churches and Organs (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - France (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Negatives (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Rolande Falcinelli (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Langlais (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Messing (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Tournemire (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Postcard Collection (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Postcard Collection & Miniatures (Box 13, Folder 42)
- Audio Material, 1953-2006; IX.
  This series contains a variety of audio formats including cassettes, CDs, multiple sized reel to reel tapes, and one VHS. The first section of this series includes select cassettes of Dr. Lord's weekly half-hour program on WQED-FM called "Lord on Bach." This program played from January 4, 1978 and ran through until the Christmas season of that same year. On cassette in this series are also interviews with Dr. Lord. On reel-to-reel tape, this collection includes a variety of performance master recordings from Heinz Chapel, Paris, and England. Many of these materials are unlabeled. Some audio was copied from the family's collection and is only represented in digital format.